Guide to the Henri Chopin Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Cinquième Saison and OU Files, 1960-2009; Series II; 1.88; (5 boxes)
  - OU Files
    - Bertini, Gianni, 1965-2009, undated (Box 14)
      Includes letter from Gianni Bertini to Brigitte Chopin, 2009 February 9
    - Blaine, Julien, 1978-1986 (Box 14)
    - Burroughs, William S., 1971-1977 (Box 14)
    - Cahn, Marcelle, 1968-1972 (Box 14)
    - Charmoy, Cozette de, 1969-2003, undated (Box 14)
    - Charmoy, Cozette de (continued), 1969-2003, undated (Box 15)
    - Cobbing, Bob, 1974-1984 (Box 15)
    - Corfou, Michel, 1972-2002, undated (Box 15)
    - Grey, Rodney, 1973-2002, undated (Box 16)
    - Costine, Jacques, 1970-1973 (Box 16)
    - Davies, Hugh, circa 1973-2001 (Box 16)
    - Degottex, Jean, 1973, undated (Box 16)
    - Dufrêne, François, 1970-1982 (Box 16)
    - Faucheux, Pierre, 1970 April-August (Box 16)
    - Ferro, Pier Luigi, undated (Box 16)
    - Furnival, John, circa 1967-1995 (Box 16)
    - Garnier, Pierre, 1979-2006 (Box 16)
    - Gerz, Jochen, 1970-1972 (Box 16)
    - Gette, Paul-Armand, undated (Box 16)
    - Gisiger, Hansjörg, 1969-1976 (Box 16)
    - Golyscheff, Jef, 1969-1971 (Box 16)
    - Gómez de Liaño, Ignacio, 1971-1998, undated (Box 16)
    - Guitet, James, 1984-1990, undated (Box 16)
    - Gysin, Brion, 1973-1985, undated (Box 16)
    - Hausmann, Raoul, 1966-1970 (Box 16)
    - Heidsieck, Bernard, 1970-1992, undated (Box 16)
    - Hutchins, Alice, circa 1966-1993 (Box 16)
    - Janco, Marcel, 1970-1974 (Box 16)
    - Jessemin, Aude, 1973-1977 (Box 16)
    - Kosice, undated (Box 17)
    - Arrigo, Lora-Totino, 1973-2004 (Box 17)
    - De Melo e Castro, Ernesto, 1966-1977 (Box 17)
    - Maccheroni, Henri, 1973-1988, undated (Box 17)
    - Moineau, Jean-Claude, circa 1967-1969 (Box 17)
    - Neuhuys, Paul, 1967-1977 (Box 17)
    - Neuhuys, Thierry, 1977-1990, undated (Box 17)
    - Neuhuys, Luc, 1976-2003 (Box 17)
    - Norguet, François, 1969-1987, undated (Box 17)
    - Novak, Ladislav, 1969-1982 (Box 17)
    - Hap Béla, 1972 June 25 (Box 17)
    - Pélieu, Claude, circa 1965-1995 (Box 17)
    - Peire, Luc, 1965-1985 (Box 17)
    - Philippe, Jean-Loup, 1965-2006, undated (Box 17)
    - Phillips, Tom, 1970-1976, undated (Box 17)
    - Rancillac, undated (Box 17)
    - Seuphor, Michel, 1974-1993 (Box 17)
    - Da Silva, Joaquim Antonio, 1971-1972 (Box 17)
    - Spatola, Adriano, 1979-1995 (Box 17)
    - Themerson, Stefan, undated (Box 17)
    - Verbrugghen, Jo, 1977-1993, undated (Box 17)
    - Urbin Choffray, Francine, circa 1990-2007 (Box 17)
    - De Vree, Paul, 1971-2003, undated (Box 17)
    - Zurbrugg, Nicolas, circa 1969-1997; 5 (Box 18)
- Artwork, 1967-2006; Series III; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series II consists of artwork by Chopin.
  - Photographs of artwork, 1994
  - The London Underground, undated
  - Le Leigh, undated (Box 19)
  - Untitled, undated; 2 (Box 19)
  - Allée de la beauté des jardins de Brigitte et Philippe, 2004 Jul 14 (Box 19)
  - La marche avec la vie, undated (Box 19)
  - Découvertes de l'Actuel, 2001 Jun (Box 19)
  - La chevauchée de maître, undated (Box 19)
  - + Monay Plus, undated (Box 19)
  - Géographie idéale, 1986 Oct (Box 19)
  - He was ex-lieutenant SS, undated (Box 19)
  - Untitled, 1993, undated (Box 19)
  - Filles du gaufrage, 1992
  - A game for April, 1985 April 4
  - Untitled, undated (Box 19)
  - La robe alphabétique tout espace et élégance, undated (Box 19)
  - La danse des §: "écrite à côté, undated (Box 19)
  - Fastidious mini pads, 1973 (Box 19)
  - Hommage à Françoise Barrière, 1975 (Box 19)
  - Hommage à Christian Clozier, 1975
  - Chemins, 1993?
  - Untitled, undated; 2 (Box 19)
  - Cadence de c (do), 1991
  - Poème fainéant, 1991
  - 1991: les orgues légères du blason de Serge Béguier
  - 11111111111111111111.0000000000000000000 zéros pour un vitrail puissant, 1992
  - Mathématiques:e, nombre incommensurable qui sert de base aux logarithmes népériens (e= 2,71828...), 1993
  - PAN de mur orné des vitraux alphabétiques en 2000, circa 2000
  - Jeux floraux, 1990
  - Untitled, undated
  - Kafka Chopin, 1992
  - Empreintes sur les Andes, 1992
  - Spaghetti Decorated Ltd or Desdemona solid, 1974
  - Henri, Jean oui à défaut on les fait: 25 ans Jean et moi. Voilà, undated
  - On recherche les tueurs, 1967
  - Henri Chopin: Graphpoemachines, 2006
  - Group of six reproductions, 2001 (Box 19)
  - Revue expresse, undated (Box 19)
  - Poesia sonora II, 1973 (Box 19)
  - Le Centre Tréméac vous présente ses meilleurs voeux pour cette nouvelle année, 1994 (Box 19)
  - Henri Chopin: Sonic memory, Norwich Gallery, 14 January to 14 February 1998 (Box 19)
  - Ozalids, undated
- Works by Others, 1948-2006; Series IV; 1.04; (3 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by artist or author name. Filed at the end of the alphabetic run are OU artists, arranged alphabetically by artist name. Filed at the end of the series is unsorted artwork and mail art, arranged alphabetically by artist name.
  Series IV consists of artwork and writings by others, including OU artists and various mail artists.
  - Aeschbacher, Arthur, undated
  - Arcand, Pierre André, 1999; 1; (1 computer disk) (Box 19)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Computer disks are restricted. Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0001, Saprithèque.
  - Autrand, Charles, 1970-1971 (Box 19)
  - Batbedat, Vincent, 1990
  - Belleguie, André, 1979 (Box 19)
  - Bertola, Carla, 1989 (Box 19)
  - Boussand, Marcel, 1975-1987, undated (Box 19)
  - Breger, Udo, 1972
  - Brunson, Bill, undated (Box 19)
  - Burke, Herbert, undated (Box 19)
  - Chaminade, Jacques, undated
  - Clercq, Maurice de, undated (Box 19)
  - Collet, Michel, 1995
  - Cox, Ken, 1968
  - Crozier, Robin, 1971-1974, undated (Box 19)
  - Dana, Llys, 1977-1997, undated (Box 19)
  - Dróżdż, Stanisław, 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - DSH (Dom Sylvester Houédard), undated (Box 19)
  - Duchêne, Gérard, undated (Box 19)
  - Fontana, Giovanni, 2005 (Box 19)
  - Fuksa, Zdenek, 1969 (Box 19)
  - Gaillard, Jean-Jacques, 1972-1973
  - Hanson, Sten, 1972, undated (Box 19)
  - Herel, Petr, undated (Box 19)
  - Higgins, Dick, 1967, undated (Box 19)
  - Hobba, Leigh, 1991
  - Hubaut, Joël, 1997, undated (Box 19)
  - Hughes, Patrick, 1974
  - Hurtado, Eric & Marc, undated (Box 20)
  - Jani, Domus, 1983
  - Janicot, Françoise, 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Jorn, Asger, 1980
  - Kaplan, Philip, 1948-1978, undated
  - Keppler, Joseph, 1984-1985 (Box 20)
  - Koenig, Théodore, circa 1971 (Box 20)
  - Lafabrie, Bernard Gabriel, 1991, undated
  - Latal, Georges, undated (Box 20)
  - Lelie, Herman C., circa 1980-1987 (Box 20)
  - Leonard, Tom, undated (Box 20)
  - Liuzzi, Oronzo, 1987 (Box 20)
  - Mariën, Marcel, undated (Box 20)
  - Martini, 1979, undated
  - Mon, Franz, 1970 (Box 20)
  - Minarelli, Enzo, 1986
  - Mousseau, Michel, 1989, undated (Box 20)
  - Nichol, B. P., October 1978
  - Orta, Jorge, 1995, undated (Box 20)
  - Özkök, Lütfi, undated
  - Petitjean, Armand, 1960-1992 (Box 20)
  - Rougier, Vincent, 1991
  - Rühm, Gerhard, 1985-1986, undated
  - Ruppenthal, Steve, circa 1978 (Box 20)
  - Smadja, Alex, 1960-1969, undated (Box 20)
  - Strange, Allen, 1980
  - Villeglé, Jacques, undated (Box 20)
  - Wendt, Larry, 1978-1982 (Box 20)
  - Waroquier, Henry de, undated
  - Williams, Emmett, 1983
  - Xenakis, Constantin, 1983-1986
  - OU Artists
    - Albert-Birot, Pierre, 1955-1970
    - Altmann, Robert, undated (Box 20)
    - Aubertin, Bernard, 1969-1984 (Box 20)
    - Ben Doute de Tout, circa 1966-1967 (Box 20)
    - Berni, Antonio, October 1964 (Box 20)
    - Bertini, Gianni, 1965, undated (Box 20)
    - Burroughs, William S., 1965 (Box 20)
    - Cahn, Marcelle, 1957-1964
    - Charmoy, Cozette de, 1966-1990, undated (Box 20)
    - Cobbing, Bob, 1975, undated
    - Corfou, Michel, 1979-1991, undated (Box 20)
    - De Vree, Paul, 1966-1973 (Box 20)
    - Dufrêne, François, 1965-1975 (Box 20)
    - Furnival, John, 1985, undated
    - Garnier, Pierre, 1963 February 16 (Box 20)
    - Gette, Paul-Armand, 1963-1968, undated (Box 20)
    - Gisiger, Hansjörg, undated (Box 20)
    - Golyscheff, Jef, 1969
    - Guitet, James, circa 1962-1987 (Box 20)
    - Gysin, Brion, 1960-1982, undated (Box 20)
    - Haumesser, Ernest, circa 1962
    - Hausmann, Raoul, circa 1947-1967 (Box 20)
    - Heidsieck, Bernard, 1978
    - Hutchins, Alice, circa 1972-1990 (Box 21)
    - Janco, Marcel, 1969, undated
    - Jessemin, Aude, undated
    - Melo e Castro, Ernesto Manuele de, 1976 (Box 21)
    - Maccheroni, Henri, 1971-1987, undated (Box 21)
    - Moineau, Jean-Claude, undated (Box 21)
    - Neuhuys, Paul, 1965-1977 (Box 21)
    - Norguet, François, undated (Box 21)
    - Novak, Ladislav, 1975-1990 (Box 21)
    - Pelieu, Claude & Burroughs, William S., undated (Box 21)
    - Peire, Luc, undated
    - Philippe, Jean-Loup, 2000, undated (Box 21)
    - Phillips, Tom, 1970, undated (Box 21)
    - Seuphor, Michel, 1961-1994 (Box 21)
    - Da Silva, Joaquim Antonio, undated (Box 21)
    - Spacagna, Jacques, 1967-1973 (Box 21)
    - Themerson, Stephan, 1972 (Box 21)
    - Verbrugghen, Jo, undated (Box 21)
    - Wolman, Gil, circa 1971 (Box 21)
    - Zurbrugg, Nicolas, 1974-1980, undated (Box 21)
  - Unsorted, 1966-1997, undated; 3 (Box 21)
  - Mail Art
    - Corfou, Michel, circa 1975-1990 (Box 21)
    - Ensemble Vide, circa 1988 (Box 22)
    - Hubaut, Joël, undated (Box 22)
    - Laszlo, Jean-Noël, circa 2005-2006 (Box 22)
    - Norguet, François, 1977 March 7 (Box 22)
    - Pelieu, Claude, 1965 (Box 22)
    - Pénard, Rémy, circa 1996-2006 (Box 22)
    - Schraenen, Guy, 1978 (Box 22)
    - Unsorted, circa 1977-1992 (Box 22)
- Photographs, circa 1960-2000; Series V; 0.42; (1 box)
  Arranged alphabetically by subject. Photographs of Henri Chopin are filed at the beginning of the series and a folder of unsorted photographs is filed at the end.
  Series V consists of photographs of Henri Chopin and various other individuals.
  - Chopin, Henri, 1980-2000, undated; 4 (Box 23)
  - Albert-Birot, Pierre, circa 1960 (Box 23)
  - Barber, Llorenç, undated (Box 23)
  - Barrière, Françoise & Clozier, Christian, undated (Box 23)
  - Bissett, Bill, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Bertini, Gianni, undated (Box 23)
  - Burroughs, William S., undated (Box 23)
  - Charmoy, Cozette de, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Corfou, Michel, undated
  - Dufrêne, François, 1976 (Box 23)
  - Gette, Paul-Armand, 1976 (Box 23)
  - Gysin, Brion, undated
  - Hultberg, Teddy, undated (Box 23)
  - Hurtado, Eric & Marc, 1992 (Box 23)
  - Kraft, Pierre, undated (Box 23)
  - Laaban, Ilmar, undated (Box 23)
  - Lagarde, François, undated (Box 23)
  - Totino, Lora, 1971, undated (Box 23)
  - Lurie, Toby, undated (Box 23)
  - Minarelli, Enzo, 1982 (Box 23)
  - Morgan, Edwin, 1978 (Box 23)
  - Noël, Bernard, undated (Box 23)
  - Novak, Ladislav, 1976, undated (Box 23)
  - Peire, Luc, undated (Box 23)
  - Philippe, Jean-Loup, undated (Box 23)
  - Rebotier, Jacques, undated (Box 23)
  - Rothenberg, Jerome, undated (Box 23)
  - Ruppenthal, Steve, undated (Box 23)
  - Shimodo, Seiji, undated (Box 23)
  - Spatola, Adriano, undated (Box 23)
  - Zurbrugg, Nicolas, 1984, undated (Box 23)
  - Unsorted, 1993, undated (Box 23)
- Writings, 1952-2007; Series VI; 6.42; (15 boxes) + 2 objects
  Not arranged in any particular order.
  Series VI consists of drafts of writings by Chopin, including a work in progress, "Les milles pensées," that was originally housed in two suitcases.
  - J'ose, undated; 3 (Box 24)
  - Alphabet pour Gratte-ciel, undated
  - Huitième et dernier livre, undated (Box 24)
  - La mutation du corps "exige" 2002, circa 2002 (Box 24)
  - La chair des siècles, undated (Box 24)
  - Les filtres, 2003 (Box 24)
  - Les lectures infinies, undated (Box 24)
  - Postface ... aux 3 J'ose!, undated (Box 24)
  - Après Vienne, undated (Box 25)
  - La poetique = savoir exact, undated (Box 25)
  - Quelques racines, undated (Box 25)
  - Le dernier livre des Riches Heures Alphabétiques des Chopins, circa 1981 (Box 25)
  - Evasion, undated (Box 25)
  - Ramona et Juanito: pièce statique, 1964 (Box 25)
  - Vivre pour vivre, undated (Box 25)
  - Ernestine, le dernier roman du monde, 1963 (Box 25)
  - Les voix autres, undated (Box 25)
  - The sauce is poisoned, undated (Box 25)
  - Quelques réflexions, undated (Box 25)
  - La cathédrale, undated (Box 25)
  - Textes sur arts et phonétique, undated (Box 25)
  - La crevette amoureuse, undated (Box 25)
  - Les inventeurs des voix, undated (Box 25)
  - Quelques racines (mes passages depuis la marche de la mort), undated (Box 26)
  - Celui qui n'a jamais pu voyager vers la lune, undated (Box 26)
  - Sol Air (fragments), undated (Box 26)
  - Le silence lance l'air, undated (Box 26)
  - Poésie sonore internationale, circa 1977-2004; 6 (Box 26)
  - Poésie sonore internationale (continued), circa 1977-2004, undated (Box 27)
  - Toute la série 1984, Précieux, 1952-2007; 1; (2 computer disks) (Box 27)
    Computer disks are restricted. Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0002, Henri Chopin. "Croquins 1952-1954"; Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0003, Musique acataleptique.
  - Tests, circa 1953-1997; 3 (Box 27)
  - Classes - performances - remixes; Vienna Poetry School, 2004 October (Box 28)
  - En guise d'auto-biographie, forcement incomplete, circa 1992 (Box 28)
  - Poésie sonore internationale, undated (Box 28)
  - Le dernier livre des riches heures alphabétiques des chopins, undated (Box 28)
  - J'ose!, undated (Box 28)
  - Glissendos pour voix unique, 1990-1991 (Box 28)
  - Communiqué de la CEE by C. de Chamoy, undated (Box 28)
  - Altagor: poésie sonore, undated (Box 28)
  - The immature world, undated (Box 28)
  - Notes & correspondence, 1983-1998, undated (Box 28)
  - Dance chants!, undated (Box 28)
  - Taylor Square Arts Festival Association, 1992 (Box 28)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 28)
  - Photographs, printed material, and miscellaneous (Box 28)
  - Hors langage, 1973 (Box 29)
  - Ruth & Marvin Sackner Archive of Concrete and Visual Poetry, undated (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous writings, 3 (Box 29)
  - Printed material, 2 (Box 30)
  - Les milles pensées, 2 (Box 30)
  - Les milles pensées (continued), 3 (Box 31)
  - Le milles pensées (continued), 6 (Box 32)
  - Le milles pensées (continued), 5 (Box 33)
  - Le milles pensées (continued), 6 (Box 34)
  - Le milles pensées (continued), 6 (Box 35)
  - Le milles pensées (continued), 3 (Box 36)
  - Brown suitcase originally housing a portion of Les milles pensées (Box 123 (Art))
  - Black suitcase originally housing a portion of Les milles pensées (Box 124 (Art))
- Audiovisual Material, 1957-2007; Series VII; 15.62; (46 boxes) + 3 objects
  Series VII includes non-commercial and commercially released audiovisual material containing performances, interviews, studio recordings, and other recordings documenting the work of Henri Chopin and other musicians and poets. The Sound Recordings subseries includes sound recordings by Chopin and others across several formats. Most of the reel-to-reel audiotapes by Chopin were likely used in his performances. The Video Recordings subseries includes VHS, BetacamSP, and DVD recordings of Chopin and his contemporaries. The Other Audiovisual Material subseries contains digital audiotapes and computer disks by Chopin and various sound recording equipment owned by Chopin, including three reel-to-reel tape recorders, two microphones, and an audiotape cutter and scissors.
  Organized into three subseries: Sound Recordings, Video Recordings, and Other Audiovisual Material.
  Boxes 37-53 and 72 (sound recordings): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 81 (computer disks): ‡a Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Boxes 54-71 and 73-80 (sound and video) Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Sound Recordings
    Parenthetical codes were assigned by the dealer. Codes correspond to the dealer description received with the collection.
    This subseries is organized under headings by format: reel-to-reel tapes, 10" and 12" vinyl sound discs, 7" vinyl sound discs, audiocassettes (commercially released and non-commercial), non-commercial compact discs, and commercially released compact discs.
    - Reel-to-reel tapes
      Boxes 37-53 (sound recordings): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      Includes works by Chopin and works by others.
      - Altagor / Vree / Heidsieck (PT 110), undated; 1; 00:12:42 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886268)
        Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Amirkhanian / Novak / Rimbaud (Chopin) (PT 166), undated; 1; 00:07:24; The program is distorted at times. (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886276)
      - Amirkhanian, Charles. "From CA to HC. Contains 5 tracks" (PT 33), 1970-1972; 1; 00:22:42 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886284)
      - "Atelier Creation Radiophonique" (PT 17 A)(1 of 3), 1988; 1; 00:49:38; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 49, Item barcode 39002104507034)
      - "Atelier Creation Radiophonique" (PT 17 B)(2 of 3), 1988; 1; 00:50:34; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 49, Item barcode 39002104507042)
      - "Atelier Creation Radiophonique" (PT 17 C)(3 of 3), 1988; 1; 00:37:42 (Box 49, Item barcode 39002104507059)
      - Battier, Marc. "Verbes comme ceuillir" (PT 81), 1980 June; 1; 00:12:19 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886292)
        Creation: Festival International dei [?], Experimentaves, Bourses
      - Battier, Marc. "Verbes comme ceuillir" (PT 44), 1980; 1 (Box 47, Item barcode 39002104507067)
        stéréo
      - Behaert, J. "John Schmitz is the message" (PT 114), 1972 November; 1; 00:08:04 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886300)
        Mills College
      - Bekaert. Untitled (PT 210), 1971; 1; 00:36:15; The program is distorted at times. It was recorded at a very high level. (Box 37, Item barcode 39002109888710)
        Prospect, Karl Marx, 2nd of 4, 11-40 - 12.00; Tape 1, red, green
      - Bosseur, Jean Yves. "Anna Livia's awake" (PT 111), undated; 1; 00:35:58 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886318)
      - Bosseur, Jean Yves. "Anna Livia's awake" (PT 185), undated; 1; 00:35:32; The audio speeds up at the start of the tape. (Box 52, Item barcode 39002109889684)
      - Brahms, Johannes. "Vier Gesänge für Frauenchor" (PT 86), undated; 1; 00:31:50; The program is distorted at times. It ends abruptly. (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886326)
      - Burke, Herbert. "Experiment 'en progrès' with sound texts" (PT 183), 1976 August; 1; 00:21:27; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886334)
        Presented in part at the 1976 Sound Poetry Festival. Speed 7 1/2, stereo. Recording time: approx. 25 minutes.
      - Chopin / Hanson. "Doubble extension" (PT 75), undated; 1; 00:08:05 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886342)
        15" stereo CLIR, mono full spin
      - Chopin/Hanson. "Tête-a-tête" (PT 133), undated; 1; 00:03:40; The program was recorded at a very high level. (Box 37, Item barcode 39002109888728)
      - Chopin / Wendt. "Voyage to California" (PT 48), 1983 May; 1; 00:20:09 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886359)
        S.J.S.U.; two-channel 15 ips, 1/2 track, NAB Eq
      - Chopin, Henri. "Cher Cher/pizzicati" (PT 90), 1987; 1; 00:07:09 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002109888736)
        cher cher, 7'7", 19 cm; pizzicati, 6'08
      - Chopin, Henri. "La fuite des dels jamais fixes" (PT 91), 2003 October; 1; 00:09:38 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002109888751)
      - Chopin, Henri. "Chocs, bouche, voix" (PT 92), 2005 May; 1; 00:11:34 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002109888777)
        audio-poeme (un seul instrument: bouche, voix & HC.); 19 cm/s, stereo, duree 11 minutes trente secondes
      - Chopin, Henri. "7 o émission / 8 o émission" (PT 93), undated; 1; 00:27:49; A high amount of hiss can be heard on the tape. The program was recorded at a very low level. (Box 37, Item barcode 39002109888769)
      - Chopin, Henri. "Reprise des raclements sur les monts partout" (PT 94), 2004 April; 1; 00:12:05; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 37, Item barcode 39002109888785)
      - Chopin, Henri. "Les flaques flics / Le glissements sur les peaux" (PT 83), 2004 Aug/Sept; 1; 00:30:18 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886367)
        Contents of the reel include the following: 5. les flaques flics 08:50, 6. les glissements sur les peaux 22:10, total environ: 32 minutes.
      - Chopin, Henri. "Reliefs sur reliefs pour une vie reelle" (PT 84), 2005 April; 1; 00:31:40 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886375)
        Information included with the reel reads: stereo 19 cm/s; bouche et voix de l'auteur; recherche contre les silences imposes par toutes les religions.
      - Chopin, Henri. "La cavalcade échevelée" (PT 85), 1983 December; 1; 00:04:47 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886383)
        Tracks are listed on the back of the reel. They are as follows:
        Saintes- Phonies 1983-87
        1. "a [?]ieds", 3'08", 19 cm
        2. "en R majeur", 4' 40", 19 cm
        3. "soufflee", 3'43", 19 cm
        4. "Soubre_sautante", 5', 19 cm
        5. "de[?]echee", 2'35", 19 cm
        6. "dialogue de sourds", 5'49, 38 cm
        7. "abyssale", 3'20, 19 cm
        8. "cavalcade Echevelee", 5'
        9. "galo[p]ante", 8'40", 19 cm
      - Chopin, Henri. "Faire l'amour au micros" (PT 88), 1971 December 21; 1; 00:28:12; For the first 14 minutes, a continuous hum can be heard. High frequency background noise can be heard for the last 14 minutes of the tape. (Box 37, Item barcode 39002109888793)
        Note on the back cover reads: Dear Henri: This is the original. - Jan
      - Chopin, Henri. "Les chutes syncopées" (PT 87), 2004 November; 1; 00:19:32 (Box 37, Item barcode 39002109888744)
      - Chopin, Henri. "La vie pénètre après des siècles de radures religieuses" (PT 82), 2006 March - April; 1; 00:17:06 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886391)
        The back cover reads: audio offert a Matteo d'Amrosio; bouche et voix de l'auteur. It was recorded in stereo at 19 cm, single track, 17 minutes.
      - Chopin, Henri. "Symphonie du nez aux vibrisses" (PT 80), 2004 December - 2005 January; 1; 00:25:30 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886409)
      - Chopin, Henri. "Les pirouettes vocales pour les pirouettements vocaux en 1995" (PT 78), 1; 00:11:05 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886417)
      - Chopin, Henri. "Discours des ministres" (PT 76), undated; 1; 00:18:42 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886425)
        Chercher 7'05", 19 cm.
      - Chopin, Henri. "La peur - 1958-1970" (PT 74), 1971; 1; 00:20:38; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 42, Item barcode 39002109886433)
        Stereo, 19cm/s. or 7 1/2. Information on the reel also reads 15'53". Production: Sveriges radio.
      - Chopin, Henri. "Vivre pour vivre No 4" (PT 73), 2006; 1; 00:28:03 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002109887688)
        Speed 7 1/2, 30'; bande originale; piece en finale pour le theatre en oratorio du meme nom, voix et bouches exlusives de l'auteur
      - Chopin, Henri. "Vivre pour vivre feu pour feu" (PT 72), 2005; 1; 00:19:44 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002109887696)
        Bob Cobbing E Colony; 7 1/2 ips., 6 mins, performers Bob Cobbing and Peter Finch (jewr harp) made in Cardiff University studio, 1973; pour Marie-Cecile Miessner; Duree: 19 minutes 20, bouche et voix de l'auteur; ainsi que le studio, realise avec 2 magnetos; stereo, 19 cm
      - Chopin, Henri. "Pêche de nuit" (PT 71), 1957; 1; 00:11:48; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 43, Item barcode 39002109887704)